Guide to the American Wind Symphony Orchestra Records, 1957-2012 AIS.1981.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Wind Symphony Orchestra Records
1957-2012
ULS Archives & Special Collections
American Wind Symphony Orchestra
AIS.1981.19
27.5 Linear Feet 28 boxes
This collection documents the work and performances of the American Wind Symphony Orchestra, founded in 1957 by conductor Robert Boudreau. The records in the collection include fundraising documents, personnel records, programs, publicity, financial records, project files, and photos, along with substantial documentation of the AWSO's tours and performances between 1960 and the late 1980s. There is also some audio and video documentation of performances by the AWSO.
Access Restrictions
Access to the following records is restricted until 75 years after the date of creation: Personnel records and applications in Series III, Subseries 2 and employee tax documents in Series IV. Until then researchers can access the records by signing a confidentiality agreement. Please contact Archives & Special Collections for more information.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the American Wind Symphony Orchestra, December 1981.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in 14 series.
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Fundraising
Series III: Exective Committee and Board of Directors,
Series IV: Personnel
Series V: Financial
Series VI: Programs
Series VII: Womens Association
Series VIII: Publicity
Series IX: Educational Programs, Festivals, and Other Projects,
Series X: Concerts and Tours
Series XI: Photographic Materials
Series XII: Moving Image Material
Series XIII: Audio Recordings
Series XIV: Oversized Materials
History
The American Wind Symphony Orchestra (AWSO) was founded by Robert Boudreau in 1957, after he moved to Pittsburgh to teach at Duquesne University. He envisioned a "floating orchestra," which would perform from a barge at docks and ports, taking high-level instrumental music outside of the concert hall to communities across the country. The AWSO was initially funded by the H.J. Heinz company and Duquesne University and performed their first season's shows from a converted coal barge named Point Counterpoint. The original barge was replaced by Point Counterpoint II in 1976 during the United States Bicentennial. Still an active performing organization in 2017, the American Wind Symphony has performed throughout America, Canada, Europe, and the Caribbean for over 50 years, commissioning over 400 new compositions and arrangements. The AWSO remains a committed proponent of the wind symphony repertoire through its active program of commissions and performances, as well as American Wind Symphony Editions, which sells musical scores, many arranged or composed for the AWSO.
Previous Citation
American Wind Symphony Orchestra Records, 1957-2012, AIS.1981.19, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Pittsburgh Symphony Society Records, 1927-1964, AIS.1966.16, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Pittsburgh Chamber Music Society Records, 1961-2009, AIS.1998.51, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Penn Theater, Pittsburgh, Pa., Records AIS.1968.06, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the American Wind Symphony Orchestra (AWSO) document the organization's creative work, programming, and public stature from its founding in 1957 through 2012, with particular focus on the group's administration, personnel, performances, and special projects. Taken together, the records document the popularity and growth of the organization through personnel records and biographies of performers, commissioned works, concert programs and advertising, as well as administrative records such as correspondence and financial records. Of particular note is the large volume of correspondence to and from the AWSO regarding sponsorship and funding, compositions and commissions, advertisements, performances, and other administrative issues. Additionally, the personnel records, project files, and concert programs document the group's artistic work through biographies and applications of AWSO members and guest artists, an extensive run of concert programs and program notes, information about particular concert venues at which the AWSO performed, and records about educational programs, festivals, and other special events planned and carried out by AWSO. Finally, the photographs and audiovisual media, including headshots and professional photos, candid photographs, and audio and film recordings of AWSO performances, lend visual and auditory context to the other record series in the collection.
Wind ensembles -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- 20th century; Symphony orchestras -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Boudreau, Robert Austin; American Wind Symphony Orchestra
- Correspondence, 1957-2010; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence from the American Wind Symphony Orchestra. While the subjects of correspondence are varied, common topics are logistics and advertisement for upcoming performances, letters between the AWSO and composers or guest artists, correspondence and memos about the work of the AWSO board and committees, and fundraising requests and acknowledgements. The records in this series are arranged in chronological order.
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Financial, 1964-1982; IV.
    This series contains information about the finances of the American Wind Symphony Orchestra, including budgets, tax information, financial statements, and insurance information. Of particular note are the folders relating to the construction, financing, and insurance for Point Counterpont II, the barge/performance space that was created for AWSO in 1976. The series is arranged chronologically.
    - Barge Construction, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Barge Construction, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Barge Construction, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Barge Construction, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Payroll, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - General, 1959-1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Income, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Income, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Income, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Tax Return, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Tax Return, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Tax Return, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Tax Return, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Tax Return, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Tax Info, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Tax Info, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Tax Info, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Tax Info, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Tax Info, 1974-1977 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Checking Account, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Checking Account, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Checking Account, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Financial Statements, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Financial Statements, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Budget, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Budget, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Budget, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Budget, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Budget, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Budget, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Budget, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Budget, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Budget, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Budget, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Budget, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Budget, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Budget, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Budget, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Funds, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Bicentennial tour, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Tidewater (Point Counterpoint II), 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Tidewater (Point Counterpoint II) (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Employee Tax Return, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Disbursements, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Disbursements, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Disbursements, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Vessel Mortgage, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Vessel Insurance, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Insurance, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Insurance, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Insurance, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Insurance, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Insurance, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Insurance, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Insurance, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Fundraising, 1960-1987; II.
  This series documents the American Wind Symphony Orchestra's fundraising efforts, including correspondence with donors and potential donors, budget and tax records, and checks. Some folders also contain annual reports and other documentation from organizations that funded the AWSO. This series is arranged in chronological order.
  - Fundraising, 1960-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fundraising, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Fundraising, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fundraising, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fundraising, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Fundraising, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fundraising, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Fundraising, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Fundraising, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fundraising, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fundraising, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fundraising, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fundraising, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fundraising, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fundraising, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fundraising, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fundraising, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fundraising, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fundraising, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Point Counterpoint II, 1973-76 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Point Counterpoint II, 1980-83 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Executive Committee and Board of Directors, 1974-1989; III.
  Series contains minutes, correspondence, member lists and notes from the AWSO Board of Directors and Executive Committee. It also contains a copy of the By-Laws of the AWSO.
  - By-Laws, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors, 1971-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Board of Directors Minutes, 1975-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Member Lists, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Notes, unidentified AWSO Committee, 1973-74 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Personnel, 1962-1982; IV.
  This series contains information largely about the performing personnel of the American Wind Symphony Orchestra, including brief biographies for musicians selected for AWSO concerts and tours, personnel files, and applications from instrumentalists, many of which contain handwritten notes about their auditions. This series has been arranged into two subseries. The first contains correspondence with, biographical sketches of, and contracts with guest artists, commissioned composers, and other AWSO collaborators. The second contains applications, contracts, correspondence, and biographical information from musicians hired by AWSO.
  - Guest artists, composers, and collaborators, 1961-1984; 1.
    This sub series contains correspondence, biographical sketches, and other information on guest artists who performed with the AWSO, composers commissioned by AWSO, and other special guests involved in AWSO tours or performances. This subseries is organized alphabetically.
    - Sam Akpabot, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - David Amram, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Per Arnoldi, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Robert Russell Bennett, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Elmer Bernstein, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Ann Beigel, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Anne C. Bolanis, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Robert Bordreau, 1967-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Debra Borkovich, No Date (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Josie Carey, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Jacques Casterede, No Date (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Jerome P. Cavanagh, No Date (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Siv Cedering Fox, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - George Djurkovic, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Dizzy Gillespie, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Samuel J. Hazo, No Date (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The Iron Clad Agreement (Musical Group), 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Ellen Kight, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Robert Kirby, 1971-1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Zane Knauss, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Anton Kuerti, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - John C. Laffin, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Christian Lantzsch, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Karen MacArthur, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Lila Manhart, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Robert McBride, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - James Minty, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Lily Peters, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Marta Ptaszynska, No Date (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Dravo Quick, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Bernard Rogers, No Date (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Ronald Rogers, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Alexander Rudajev, No Date (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Milton Shapp, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Eddie Skoller, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Jean Smith, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Richard Strauss, No Date (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - James Stumpter, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - David Syrotink, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Jamee Todd, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Paul Tracey, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Ted Washington, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Michael Wilson, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Phil Woods, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Gene Young, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mary Ytarria, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Commissions, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - AWSO Personnel Records, 1965-1984; 2.
    This sub series contains general information on instrumental performers of the American Wind Symphony, who were generally hired for a particular season or festival. It contains applications, along with notes on auditions, signed contracts, correspondence, and brief biographies of performers. This sub series is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Applications and contracts, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Biographical information, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Personnel correspondence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Applications, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Contracts, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Biographical information, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Applications, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Biographical information, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Contracts, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - List of personnel, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Contracts, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Applications, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Biographical information and contracts, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Applications and contracts, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Applications and contracts, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Applications and contracts, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Applications and contracts, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Applications and contracts, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Biographical information, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Applications and contracts, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Contracts, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Applications, biographical information, and contracts, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Applications and contracts, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Applications and contracts, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Applications and correspondence, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Applications and correspondence, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Soloists, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Programs, 1958-1988; V.
  This series contains programs from the American Wind Symphony Orchestra's performances, some for individual concerts and some for tours comprising many individual concerts. Also included in this series are drafts and early versions of program notes, as well as correspondence with companies discussing advertising placement in AWSO's programs. The series is arranged chronologically.
  - Programs, 1958-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1981-1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Program Note Drafts, 1964-1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Ad Placement, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ad Placement, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Ad Placement, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ad Placement, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ad Placement, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ad Placement, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Ad Placement, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Ad Placement, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Ad Placement, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Womens Association, 1962-1967; VI.
  This series contains information on the Women's Association of the American Wind Symphony Orchestra, an organization dedicated to supporting and promoting the Orchestra. Series contains correspondence, tax records, bylaws, member lists, and pamphlets.
  - Reports, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1965-67 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Flyers/Pamphlets, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Bylaws, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Members, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Publicity, 1959-2012; VII.
  This series contains publicity about the American Wind Symphony Orchestra, including news clippings, from the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, New York Times, and local and regional papers that covered AWSO's performances. There are also magazines featuring articles on the AWSO, pamphlets and flyers advertising concerts and other events, and AWSO press releases.
  - Newspaper Articles, 1959-2012; 1.
    This subseries contains original newspaper clippings and photocopies of newspaper clippings about the American Wind Symphony Orchestra from local, national, and regional publications. This subseries has been arranged chronologically by year.
    - Newspaper Articles, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper Articles, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Articles, No Date (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Magazine Articles, 1956-1989; 2.
    This subseries contains articles about the American Wind Symphony Orchestra from various national and local magazines. The records in this subseries are kept in chronological order by decade.
    - Magazine articles, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Magazine articles, 1960-1969 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Magazine articles, 1960-1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Magazine articles, 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Magazine articles, 1970-1979 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Magazine articles, 1980-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Flyers & Booklets, 1959-2012; 3.
    The subseries contains flyers and booklets created for patrons of American Wind Symphony Orchestra concerts. This sub series has been arranged into four folders by year.
    - Flyers & Booklets, 1959-1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Flyers & Booklets, 1977-1981 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Flyers & Booklets, 1978-2012 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Flyers & Booklets, No Date (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Press Releases and Announcements, 1959-1985; 4.
    This subseries contains American Wind Symphony Orchestra press releases and other advertising material from 1959-1985, including announcements of upcoming concerts, tours, and some texts for radio advertisements. This subseries has been arranged chronologically by year.
    - Press Releases, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Press Releases, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Press Releases, 1962-1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Press Releases, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Press Releases, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Press Releases, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Press Releases, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Press Releases, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Press Releases, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Press Releases, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Press Releases, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Press Releases, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Press Releases, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Press Releases, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Press Releases, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Press Releases, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 23)